GAEL GENET

WEB DEVELOPER

289-993-7500 - Oakville, ON this@ggenet.pw - www.ggenet.pw

Currently on a work permit in Canada (IEC), I am searching for a position in web development in Toronto where my past experiences and knowledge will contribute to new projects. I am interested in full-stack development (integration, front-end, back-end, databases).

- Strong skills in JavaScript, AngularJs, Ionic, Cordova, HTML, (S)CSS, Node.js, Unit testing, MySQL, MongoDB, Git
- Experience with Java, GWT, Hibernate, Android SDK
- Worked in Agile / Scrum environments
- · Fluent in both French and English

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER @ ADNEOM IN BRUSSELS, BELGIUM

(2 YEARS, FROM 09/2015 To 09/2017)

- Volunteer in the French VIE program (Volontariat International en Entreprise)
- Coached interns in hybrid mobile development
- Successfully delivered all products for each project

ADNEOM PROJECT: NODE.JS DEVELOPER @ WEARETENNIS

(8 Months, From 01/2017 To 09/2017)

- Fully developed the back-end (REST API) for both website and CMS
- Implemented unit testing to meet quality requirements
- Solved latency issues to enhance user experience
- Discussed and addressed security concerns
- Managed and implemented solutions from different service providers

Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Mocha, Redis, Docker / Scrum wearetennis.bnpparibas

WEB & HYBRID MOBILE APP DEVELOPER FOR ADNEOM @ URBANTZ

(6 Months, From 09/2015 To 11/2015, 04/2016 To 09/2016)

- Maintained and optimized the performance of the Ionic app
- Implemented google map and canvas drawing functionalities
- Added app branding features for clients
- Successfully delivered a fully custom version for a client

HTML, SCSS, AngularJs, Ionic, Cordova, Node.js, Express, MongoDB / Scrum urbantz.com

HYBRID MOBILE APP DEVELOPER FOR ADNEOM @ IMMODOO

(5 Months, From 01/2016 To 02/2016, From 09/2016 To 12/2016)

- Successfully took over the project in order to start on a v2
- Analysed business needs in order to find the best solutions
- Discussed and addressed UX, UI and performance issues
- Provided support for the Java / Cassandra back-end

HTML, SCSS, AngularJs, Ionic, Cordova, Java, Cassandra immodoo.fr

HYBRID MOBILE APP DEVELOPER FOR ADNEOM @ MOODUP!

(3 Months, From 02/2016 To 04/2016)

- · Participated in business development
- Developed new features and implemented KPI loggers
- Discussed options and solved performance issues
- · Integrated new flows and designs

HTML, SCSS, AngularJs, Ionic, Cordova, Node.js, MongoDB MoodUP on iTunes MoodUP on Google Play

ADNEOM PROJECT: HYBRID MOBILE APP DEVELOPER @ RISERS

(2 Months, From 11/2015 to 12/2015)

- Provided backup support to the existing team
- Product delivery and store deployment

AngularJs, Ionic, Cordova

EDUCATION

2013: M.Sc (COMPUTER SCIENCE) - SUPINFO - SAN FRANCISCO, CA, USA Master's thesis: Web Presence - Taking your business online

2011: B.Sc (HONS) (COMPUTER SCIENCE) - SUPINFO - TROYES, FRANCE

Internships

07/2013 TO 10/2013 - Sunrise Home PHP developer

12/2011 TO 10/2012 - CRISTALLIN Java GWT developer

07/2010 TO 10/2011 - **GRAVOTECH MARKING SAS** Java GWT developer, Custom software scripts developer (VBScript, JavaScript)